Guide to the Carroll L. V. Meeks Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Inventory, [1930s-1966?]; 18 linear feet (33 boxes, 1 folio)
  - Mounted photographs of Street Hall: exteriors, interiors and plans
    TRANSFERRED TO YALE PICTURE COLLECTION
  - Abstracts (Box 28)
  - Ackerman, James (Box 28)
  - "A" Miscellaneous (Box 28)
  - A.C.L.S. (American Council, of Learned Societies) (Box 28)
  - A.C.S.A. (Association of Collegiate Schools of Architecture) (Box 28)
  - American Institute of Architects (Box 28)
  - AIA Preservation -- Robie House (Box 28)
  - AIA Connecticut Chapter Correspondence - 1962-1966 (Box 28)
  - AIA Committee on Preservation of Historic Buildings - Memoranda, Bulletins, Circulars, etc. 1961-196_ (Box 28)
  - AIA Committee on Preservation of Historic Buildings Correspondence - 1951-196_ (Box 28)
  - AIA Committee on Preservation of Historic Buildings. Memoranda, Bulletins, Circulars, etc., 1956-1960 (Box 28)
  - AlA Journals, Newsletters Program (Box 28)
  - AIA Connecticut Chapter. Correspondence., 1955-1961. (Box 28)
  - AIA Connecticut Chapter. Memoranda, Bulletins, etc., 1961-196_ (Box 28)
  - AIA Connecticut Chapter. Memoranda, Bulletins, etc., 1955-1960 (Box 28)
  - AIA Community Development Committee (Box 28)
  - AIA Journal - Watterson, Joseph, editor (Box 28)
  - Alexander, Henry A (Box 28)
  - Alumni Board (Box 28)
  - American Academy - Rome (Box 28)
  - American Council of the Arts (Box 28)
  - American Quarterly (Box 28)
  - Amt, Gerhard J (Box 28)
  - Andrews, Wayne (Box 28)
  - Antiquarian and Landmarks Society (Box 28)
  - Architectural League - Jan. 8, 1959 (Box 28)
  - Arch. 14a (includes a good bibliography for his senior seminar on architectural scale) (Box 28)
  - Arch. 14a - clippings (Box 28)
  - Arch. 18b (Ancient and Medieval Masterworks) (Box 28)
  - Architecture 30 - 1954 (Box 28)
  - Architecture 46b - 1962 (Box 28)
  - Architecture 46b (Architectural Philosophies) (Box 28)
  - Archive, Connecticut (Box 28)
  - Arneill, Bruce (Box 28)
  - Art, History of 253a (College Architecture) (Box 28)
  - Art Gallery, Art Library (Box 28)
  - Attingham Park - 1962 (Box 28)
  - "B" Miscellaneous (Box 28)
  - Baltimore - November, 1957 (Box 28)
  - Bannister,-Turpin C., Dean (Box 28)
  - Bellinger, Davis. Company (Box 28)
  - Bibliography (Box 28)
  - Bibliography - Books - Europe '55 (Box 28)
  - Bibliography (Box 28)
  - Bibliography (Box 28)
  - Bibliography of Architectural Criticism in America. 1863-1928 (Box 29)
  - Bicknell, Peter (Box 29)
  - Bohan, Peter (Box 29)
  - Branford College Meeks a fellow of Branford) (Box 29)
  - Brewster, Kingman (Box 29)
  - Bridgeport Historical Society (Box 29)
  - Brooks, H. Allen (Box 29)
  - De La Torre Bueno, J. R (Box 29)
  - Bunnell, Mr. and Mrs. Sterling (Box 29)
  - Bush-Brown, Albert (Box 29)
  - "C" Miscellaneous (Box 29)
  - Cameron, John (Box 29)
  - Cappon, Lester J (Box 29)
  - Carrere and Hastings - Exhibit (Box 29)
  - Carrigan, Wilton (Box 29)
  - Carrott, Richard G (Box 29)
  - Century Club, N.Y (Box 29)
  - Capitals - Misc (Box 29)
  - Chafee, Richard (Box 29)
  - Cheek, Leslie (Box 29)
  - Christ-Janer, A (Box 29)
  - Clark, Mrs. Henry M (Box 29)
  - Class of '28 - C.L.V.M (Box 29)
  - Cohen, J (Box 29)
  - Colchester - Hebron Project. HABS (Box 29)
  - Cochran, Alexander (Box 29)
  - College Art Assoc., 1956- (Box 29)
  - Collins, P (Box 29)
  - Columbia (Box 29)
  - Committee to Preserve National Capitol (Box 29)
  - Conn. Hist. Soc (Box 29)
  - Congress of the History of Art (Box 29)
  - Connecticut Architectural Examinations. Carroll L. V. Meeks (Box 29)
  - Connecticut Building Congress (Box 29)
  - Conant, Kenneth (Box 29)
  - Conklin, George (Box 29)
  - Coolidge, John (Box 29)
  - J. Hamilton Coulter (Box 29)
  - Creese, Walter (Box 29)
  - Cummings, Abbott (Box 29)
  - Cunningham, Charles C (Box 29)
  - Customs, 1962 (Box 29)
  - "D" Miscellaneous (Box 29)
  - Danes, Gibson A (Box 29)
  - Davies, J.H.V (Box 29)
  - Dearstyne, H (Box 29)
  - Minutes - Director's Meeting (Box 29)
  - Donnelly, Marion Card (Box 29)
  - Downes J, Neil (Box 29)
  - Drawing Project (Box 29)
  - Duplicate Clippings and Memorabilia (Box 29)
  - "E" Miscellaneous (Box 29)
  - East Haddam - Opera - Mrs. Kage (Box 29)
  - Edgartown (Box 29)
  - Egbert, D (Box 29)
  - Ellner, Anthony (Box 29)
  - Encyclopedia Brit
    - Stewart, Donald (Box 29)
    - Dodge, John (Box 29)
  - Europe, 1962 (Box 29)
  - Eveson, Norma (Box 29)
  - Exhibitions (Box 29)
  - Exhibition of Rendering (Box 29)
  - "F" Miscellaneous (Box 29)
  - Photos/ various exhibits (Box 29)
  - Farlow, Robert (Box 29)
  - Farmington (Box 29)
  - Festival of the Arts (Box 29)
  - Fitch, James (Box 29)
  - Fitz Patrick, Thomas (Box 29)
  - Fleischner, Charles (Box 29)
  - Fletcher, Norman (Box 29)
  - Forbes, John (Box 29)
  - Ford Foundation (Box 29)
  - Ford, O'Neil (Box 29)
  - Forum, Architectural (Box 29)
  - Foster, Philip (Box 29)
  - Francis, William (Virginia Museum of Fine Arts) (Box 29)
  - Fulton, Mrs. John (Box 29)
  - George, Hardy (Box 30)
  - "G" Miscellaneous (Box 30)
  - Giedion, Sigfried (Box 30)
  - Gilbert, Creighton (Box 30)
  - Gisolfi, Diana. Prelim May 4. Final 31 May (Box 30)
  - Graduate School. Current (Box 30)
  - Great Britain (Box 30)
  - Green, Samuel (Box 30)
  - Green, Wilder (Box 30)
  - Guggenheim. 1958-1959, 1960-1961, 1961-1962, 1964-1965 (Box 30)
  - Guilford Keeping Society (Box 30)
  - Gutheim, Frederick (Box 30)
  - "H" Miscellaneous (Box 30)
  - H.A.B.S (Box 30)
  - H.A.B.S. Forms (Box 30)
  - H.A.B.S. Measured Drawings (Box 30)
  - Hacker, Arthur E. Jr (Box 30)
  - Hamilton, David S (Box 30)
  - Hamilton, George (Box 30)
  - Hammel, Richard (Box 30)
  - Harbaugh, Mrs. W. H (Box 30)
  - Harral-Wheeler House (Box 30)
  - Harris, Erdman (Box 30)
  - Harris, Harwell (Box 30)
  - Hartland Historical Society (Box 30)
  - Haskell, Douglas (Box 30)
  - Henderson, Mrs (Box 30)
  - Hersey, George (Box 30)
  - Hill, Randolph (Box 30)
  - Historic American Buildings Survey (Box 30)
  - HA 53b (Box 30)
  - HA 53a, 1962 (Box 30)
  - HA 53a 1961 (Box 30)
  - HA 53a 1960 (Box 30)
  - HA 53a (Box 30)
  - History of the School of Art and Architecture (6 p. essay) (Box 30)
  - HA 163 1969 (Box 30)
  - HA 166 (a & b) 1962, 63 (Box 30)
  - HA 200 (Box 30)
  - Hitchcock, Henry-Russell (Box 30)
  - Hoag, John (Box 30)
  - Hotchkiss, Mrs (Box 30)
  - Howarth, Thomas (Box 30)
  - Howland, Richard (Box 30)
  - Hufstader, Robert (Box 30)
  - IAAS (The Institute of Advanced Architectural Studies) (Box 30)
  - "I" Miscellaneous (Box 30)
  - Irving, Robert Grant (Box 30)
  - Robert Grant Irving. History of Art 53b (Box 30)
  - Ives, Chauncey (Box 30)
  - "J" Miscellaneous (Box 30)
  - Jacobus, John M. Jr (Box 30)
  - Janson, Richard (Box 30)
  - Jamaica (Box 30)
  - Job File (Box 30)
  - Johnson, Philip (Box 30)
  - Jones, Mellor (Box 30)
  - Jordy, William H (Box 30)
  - "K" Miscellaneous (Box 30)
  - Keith, Elmer (Box 30)
  - Kelly, Robert (Box 30)
  - Kerr, Chester (Box 30)
  - Ketchum, Morris (Box 30)
  - Koch, Robert (Box 30)
  - Kramer, Mrs. George (Box 30)
  - Krautheimer, Richard (Box 31)
  - Kubler, George (Box 31)
  - "L" Miscellaneous (Box 31)
  - Lancaster, Clay (Box 31)
  - Leffingwell Inn (Box 31)
  - Lewis, Virginia E (Box 31)
  - Lewis, Mrs. & W (Box 31)
  - Life (Box 31)
  - L'Oeil (Box 31)
  - Lockwood Mansion (Box 31)
  - Ludwig, Allan (Box 31)
  - "M" Miscellaneous (Box 31)
  - MacDonald, William L (Box 31)
  - Mack, Maynard (Box 31)
  - Macy, Nelson (Box 31)
  - Mack-Smith, Denis (Box 31)
  - Madison, Charles (Box 31)
  - Magruder, Charles (Box 31)
  - Marrinoccio, Dr. Anthony (Box 31)
  - Martin, Sir Leslie (Box 31)
  - MAS (Modern Architecture Symposium) (Box 31)
  - Mather, Austin (Box 31)
  - Mattatuck Historical Society (Box 31)
  - Mayhew, Edgar (Box 31)
  - McCormick, Thomas (Box 31)
  - McLaughlin, Herbert P (Box 31)
  - Merrill, David (Box 31)
  - Milgrome, David (Box 31)
  - Mills, Dr. Edward ' (Box 31)
  - Moore, Charles. Dept. of Architecture (Box 31)
  - Morrison, Hugh (Box 31)
  - Mumford, Lewis (Box 31)
  - Myer, John (Box 31)
  - "N" Miscellaneous (Box 31)
  - N.A.A.B. (National Architectural Accrediting Board) (Box 31)
  - National Trust (for Historic Preservation) (Box 31)
  - Neutra, Richard (Box 31)
  - New Britain Historical Society (Box 31)
  - Newcomb, Rexford (Box 31)
  - New Haven Preservation Trust (Box 31)
  - New Haven Preservation Trust, Legal (Box 31)
  - New Haven Preservation Trust, Correspondence (Box 31)
  - Plaques - and - Miscellany (Box 31)
  - New London Historical Society (Box 31)
  - New Milford Historical Society (Box 31)
  - New Haven Preservation Trust (Box 31)
  - The New Haven Preservation Trust. Carroll L. V. Meeks, President (Box 31)
  - Newman, Robert (Box 31)
  - Nichols, Frederick (Box 31)
  - Nicolletti, M (Box 31)
  - Niland, David L. (Copy of a Report on Architectural Education, Univ. of Cincinnati) (Box 31)
  - Norton, Paul (Box 31)
  - Norwalk, Conn (Box 31)
  - Norwich H.A.B.S. Project (Box 31)
  - Norwich Project (Box 31)
  - Agenda -- Minutes and Reports (Historic Preservation Organizations) (Box 31)
  - Historic Districts (Box 31)
  - Wiggin & Dana -- Legal Questions (Box 31)
  - "O" Miscellaneous (Box 31)
  - Olana (Box 31)
  - Owatonna Bank (Box 31)
  - Overby, Osmund (Box 31)
  - "P" Miscellaneous (Box 31)
  - Palmer, Frederick (Box 31)
  - Personal (Box 31)
  - Personal Library - Carroll L. V. Meeks (Box 31)
  - Notes -- Europe '51-'52 -- Rome (Box 32)
  - Parkhurst, Charles (Box 32)
  - Parris, H. W (Box 32)
  - Payne, Judel (Box 32)
  - Perfido, Len (Box 32)
  - Peterson, Charles (Box 32)
  - Pettengill, George E. A.I.A (Box 32)
  - Pevsner, Dr. Niklaus (Box 32)
  - Photostats (Recent) (Box 32)
  - Pickens, Buford (Box 32)
  - Pitkin, J. S (Box 32)
  - Placzek, Adolf K (Box 32)
  - Princeton (Box 32)
  - Progressive Architecture (Box 32)
  - Frown, Jules (Box 32)
  - "R" Miscellaneous (Box 32)
  - RR Stations. Current (Box 32)
  - Redpath, Robert (Box 32)
  - Reed, H. H (Box 32)
  - Rennell, Henry (Box 32)
  - Research Committee (Box 32)
  - Richards, J. M (Box 32)
  - Richmond City Hall (Box 32)
  - Ritchie, Andrew (Box 32)
  - Roble House (Box 32)
  - Robinson, Cervin (Box 32)
  - Rohsenow, John S (Box 32)
  - Rosenblum, Robert (Box 32)
  - Ross, Marion (Box 32)
  - Rutledge, Anna (Box 32)
  - Rudolph, Paul (Box 32)
  - "S" Miscellaneous (Box 32)
  - S.A.H. 1958, 1964-1966 General Correspondence (Box 32)
  - Saarinen, Eero (Box 32)
  - S.A.B.S. (Seven Arts Book Society) (Box 32)
  - S.A.H. Treasurers Reports, Bulletins, Newsletters, Etc. 1964-1964 (Box 32)
  - Scholle, Harding (Box 32)
  - Scott, Fitzhugh (Box 32)
  - Schreider, Louis (Box 32)
  - Scully, Vince (Box 32)
  - Meeks -- Scrapbook (Box 32)
  - Searing, Helen (Box 32)
  - Sharpe, Richard (Box 32)
  - Sizer, T (Box 32)
  - Smith, G. E. Kidder (Box 32)
  - South Windsor Historical Society (Box 32)
  - Steese, Edward (Box 32)
  - Stamford Historical Society (Box 32)
  - Stevens Estate (Box 32)
  - Summerson, John (Box 32)
  - Sweet, J.S.C (Box 32)
  - Swift, Geoffry (Box 32)
  - Syracuse (Box 32)
  - "T" Miscellaneous (Box 32)
  - Talbot (Box 32)
  - Taylor, John (Box 32)
  - Taylor, Walter A (Box 32)
  - Torrington Historical Society (Box 32)
  - Tunnard, Christopher (Box 32)
  - "U" Miscellaneous (Box 32)
  - Univ. Atlas Cement Exhibition (Box 32)
  - Universal Standard Encyclopedia (Box 32)
  - Van James (Box 32)
  - "V" Miscellaneous (Box 32)
  - "W" Miscellaneous (Box 32)
  - "W" Miscellaneous (Box 32)
  - Walker, Robert (Box 32)
  - Warren, Wm. G (Box 32)
  - Watterson, Joseph (Box 32)
  - Weinrab, Ben. Ltd (Box 32)
  - Whiffen, Marcus (Box 32)
  - Whitlock's (Box 32)
  - Williamsburg (Box 32)
  - Wittenborn (Box 32)
  - Wittkower, Rudolf (Box 32)
  - Woodbridge, F (Box 32)
  - Amity and Woodbridge Historical Society (Box 32)
  - Woodstock Historical Society (Box 32)
  - Woolsey Books (Box 32)
  - Wriston, Barbara (Box 32)
  - "X-Y-Z" Miscellaneous (Box 32)
  - Yale Press (Box 32)
  - York (Box 32)
  - Zevi, Bruno (Box 32)
  - Zucker, Paul (Box 32)
  - Papers related to the School of Architecture and miscellaneous unsorted papers (Box 33)
    Conditions Governing Access
    This box is closed to research because of university policy on access to student records.
  - Printed articles, primarily in Italian, on art and architecture (Box 34)
- Additional Material, 1600s-1978, undated; Accession 1991-M-101; 26 linear feet (26 boxes)
  Received from: Transferred from the Slides and Photographs Collection, Street Hall, 1991 Feb
  - CONNECTICUT ARCHITECTURE
    General note
    This is a file, arranged alphabetically by town name, of student papers on individual buildings throughout Connecticut. Most of the buildings seem to be single family houses, but there are also churches, town halls, taverns, and inns. The period emphasized is colonial, although there are a few 19th century buildings as well. All buildings were standing at the time the papers were written.
    - General
      - Lists of buildings proposed/covered (Box 1)
      - Bibliography (Box 1)
      - Historic American Building Survey (HABS): photographs, supplement list, copy book list (Box 1)
      - Library of Congress (Box 1)
      - History of Art 156: Early American, 1957-1958 (Box 1)
    - Ansonia - Branford (Box 1)
    - Bridgeport - Durham (Box 2)
    - East Granby - Greenwich (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - Greenwich (2 folders) - Hamburg (Box 4)
    - Hamden - New Britain (Box 5)
    - New Canaan - Norwalk (Box 6)
    - Norwich - Saybrook (Box 7)
    - Scotland - Stanwich (Box 8)
    - Stonington - Wilton (Box 9)
    - Windsor - Yantic (Box 10)
    - NEW HAVEN ARCHITECTURE
      This is the New Haven section of the Connecticut architecture file but far more extensive in plan. It was compiled as a working file for a projected architectural history of New Haven. The guide was never published in this form, but it was later reworked and published as New Haven: a Guide to Architecture and Urban Design, by Elizabeth Mills Brown in 1976.
      Particularly important in this material are photographs of the now destroyed City Hall annex and of the interior of the Davies mansion on Prospect Hill.
      The preliminary texts and photographs are grouped in folders roughly by area of New Haven.
      - General
        - Historic American Building Survey for New Haven, Fairfield, Litchfield, and Middlesex counties, 1962-1964 (Box 10)
        - New Haven material in Yale (Box 10)
      - Architectural Club of New Haven (Box 10)
      - Bank architecture (Box 10)
      - Business (alphabetical by name of building)
        - Basset (John E.) Company - Woolsey School (Box 10)
      - Educational (alphabetical by name of school) Benton School - Wooster Street School (Box 11)
      - Government and public buildings Angell Hall - YMCA (Box 11)
      - Religious buildings/cemeteries All Saints Chapel - Wooster Square Baptist Church (Box 11)
      - Residential (alphabetical by building name)
        - A-I (Box 12)
        - J-Z (Box 13–14)
      - Working papers from a Yale seminar of George Hersey co-taught with Elizabeth Mills Brown, related to New Haven guide (Box 14)
      - Oversize
        - Jonathan Riley House, Rocky Hill: plans, photographs (Box 15)
        - St. John House, Danbury: report (Box 15)
        - Plans of the Branford Room, Yale University Art Gallery, by Harvey Bartholomew Mitsui (Box 15)
        - Photographs of buildings on Orchard and Dickerman Streets (Box 15)
        - Unidentified (Box 15)
  - RAILROAD STATIONS
    This file is arranged alphabetically by town or city name. It is worldwide, and includes plans, photographs, and material collected as research material for Professor Meeks' book, The Railroad Station, New Haven, Yale University Press, 1956. The published book is still the best guide to this file. There are many things in the file, however, which are not in the book.
    - Index of U.S. railroad stations listed chronologically from 1830-1890 (Box 16)
    - Index of town or city name (Box 16)
    - Alessandro, California - Birmingham, England (Box 16)
    - Bismarck, North Dakota - Garwood Depot, Eagle Lake, Texas (Box 17)
    - Genoa, Italy - Los Angeles, California (Box 18)
    - Louisville, Kentucky - Quincy, Massachusetts (Box 19)
    - Raton, New Mexico - Zurich, Switzerland (Box 20)
  - WORKS PROGRESS ADMINISTRATION (WPA) FILES
    These files contain architectural surveys of old buildings in Connecticut. The data sheets and photographs were compiled by the WPA project in 1935-1936, preliminary to the publication of a Connecticut guide written by that project. The files are arranged alphabetically by town.
    - Index of WPA files, general (Box 21)
    - Andover - Clinton (Box 21)
    - Colchester - Groton (Box 22)
    - Guilford - Morris (Box 23)
    - Naugatuck - Roxbury (Box 24)
    - Salem - Watertown (Box 25)
    - West Hartford - Woodstock, miscellaneous (possibly duplicates) (Box 26)
- Additional Material, 1942; Accession 1993-M-016; 0.25; (1 box)
  Addition inventory by Carol King 1992 Sep
  Received from: Victoria Blair-Smith, 1992 Jul 20
  - Oil painting of Carroll L. V. Meeks done by Esther Vance, a Danish artist friend of the Meeks family, 1942 (Box 1)
- Additional Material, Circa 1929-1931 (Box 1)
  Consists of architectural drawings completed while a student and a poster advertising Italian Archiecture.